Guide to the Helen E. Hokinson Cartoons for The New Yorker
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Portfolio 7, Series VII
  - 70. "My, aren't you glad you're not a salesman!" (Box 6, Folder 94)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing, and typed on a slip attached to drawing.
  - 71. "George, is there something about the Russians that we're supposed to like?" (Box 6, Folder 95)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased partially visible caption, and typed on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 72. [Child asleep in bed, Christmas stocking hung on mantle.] (Box 10, Folder 196)
    Watercolor over pencil, 9 x 6", unsigned. Rough sketch for cover.
  - 73. [View from the shore of the ocean.] (Box 6, Folder 96)
    Watercolor and crayon, 9 7/8 x 13 7/8", 1/4" green paper tape border, unsigned.
  - 74. [Matron paddling a rowboat with one oar.] (Box 6, Folder 97)
    Gray wash over pencil, 9 3/8 x 12 1/4", rough sketch, unsigned.
  - 75. "Do you take I.O.U.'s?" (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - 76. "Alice, go look at my engagement pad and see what I'm doing." (Box 6, Folder 99)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned.
  - 77. [Matron with fishing pole at edge of stream covers her eyes as butler puts worm on the hook.] (Box 6, Folder 100)
    Black ink and watercolor over pencil, 8 3/4 x 11", unsigned. Rough sketch for cover.
  - 78. "I have two sheep in the baggage car, Gordon, they're for the lawn.", 1934 (Box 15, Folder 336)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 15 3/8 x 19". Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. AA1654 written in blue crayon and date 7/14/34 in pencil on verso.
  - 79. [View of mountain range.] (Box 10, Folder 197)
    Watercolor, 7 x 9 7/8", unsigned.
  - 80. [Scene at club meeting. Chair addressing seated members.], 1935 (Box 15, Folder 337)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 12 3/8 x 20". AA3409 written in blue crayon and date stamped JUN 8 1935 on verso.
  - 81. Petit Dejeuner. (Box 15, Folder 338)
    A sequence of eleven panel drawings. Black ink and gray wash over pencil, the drawings approximately 4 x 4" together on a sheet 20 x 13". Title written in pencil at head between first two drawings, captions written in pencil at foot of each drawing. See Series 7, drawing 9 for a sketch from this sequence.
  - 82. "Say, Cap—where's Miss Dotty DeWolf's room?" "Now don't you worry about me." (Box 15, Folder 339)
    Two drawings. Black ink and gray wash over pencil, the two drawings 8 1/4 x 6 1/4" and 5 3/4 x 7 1/4" mounted together on a sheet 13 1/2 x 20 1/4", both unsigned. Captions written in pencil at foot of drawings and cancelled. 1245/5-4/110 written in pencil on verso of mat.
  - 83. "Good news! My husband is giving me twelve hours with you for my birthday." (Box 6, Folder 101)
    Pencil, 14 x 16 3/4", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing, and typed on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 84. "They spoil him so at Bonwits." (Box 6, Folder 102)
    Pencil,.13 3/4 x 16 7/8", unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing, and typed on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 85. "Today I'm just looking around." or "Do you mind if I just look around?" (Box 6, Folder 103)
    OR "Do you happen to know of something the Holly Carollers would find refreshing?" Pencil, 13 3/4 x 16 7/8", unsigned. Both captions written in pencil at foot of drawing, and typed. on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 86. "There won't be a German prisoner in the lower berth will there?" (Box 6, Folder 104)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased partially visible captions.
  - 87. "I'm just looking to see if he says anything about New Canaan." (Box 6, Folder 105)
    Pencil, 12 1/4 x 18 3/4", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased partially visible caption. Erased notation—Reid maybe art conference would think this funny if it were a more successful writer—in right margin.
  - 88. "What makes A. J. Cronin's people get into so much trouble?" (Box 6, Folder 106)
    Pencil, 14 x 17", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased partially visible caption, with notation—(could be woman in book shop)—below.
  - 89. "Is there any danger of the tussock moth deciding to come down from Massachusetts?" (Box 6, Folder 107)
    Pencil, 14 x 17", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased partially visible captions, and typed on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 90. "I think it's wonderful to be able to do things with your hands." (Box 6, Folder 108)
    Black ink, crayon, and gray wash, 12 x 17 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased partially visible captions, and typed on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 91. [Matron in fur coat retrieving her dog from railway baggage car.] (Box 6, Folder 109)
    Pencil, 8 7/8 x 11 7/8", unsigned. Rough sketch for cover.
  - 92. "It's about two very delightful mules." (Box 6, Folder 110)
    Pencil, 13 3/4 x 16 3/4", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over and above previously erased partially visible captions, with notation—(The new Agnew Chamberlain book)—written below.
  - 93. [Matron in overalls leaning on fence looking at cornfield.] (Box 6, Folder 111)
    Colored crayons over pencil, 9 7/8 x 6 3/4", unsigned. Rough sketch for cover.
  - 94. "Je te dis, Celestine, que je ne veux pax visiter at tombe du general Grant!" (Box 6, Folder 112)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 12 1/8 x 19". Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing.
  - 95. Mrs. Fortescue made the gesture she used to attract the lowly. (Box 6, Folder 113)
    Black, gray, and pink washes over pencil, 13 7/8 x 10 1/4", rough sketch, unsigned. Title written in pencil at foot of drawing.
  - 96. Perspective drawing. (Box 10, Folder 198)
    Pencil, 6 3/8 x 5 1/8", rough sketch, unsigned.
  - 97. Drawing of an evergreen tree. (Box 10, Folder 199)
    Colored pencil, 6 x 5 1/8", rough sketch. On verso of Hokinson invoice: printed form memo of Helen E. Hokinson.
  - 98. [Woman with two small children, and older figure in foreground.] (Box 10, Folder 200)
    Watercolor and pencil, 8 1/4 x 6 1/2", rough sketch, unsigned.
  - 99. "I don't think I could ever love another short stop as much as I love Phil Rizzuto." (Box 6, Folder 114)
    Pencil, 12 1/8 x 18 5/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. Typed alternate caption—"I never really get hot under the collar until after the 1st inning"—on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 100. "I've never really made up my mind about Mozart, have you?" (Box 7, Folder 115)
    Pencil, 12 1/4 x 18 5/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over and above previously erased partially visible caption, with notation—could be in record shop—in lower left corner, and typed (including notation)on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 101. "I've decided not to wear a ribbon, even though I did spend a month in Honolulu." (Box 7, Folder 116)
    Pencil, 16 7/8 x 13 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. Typed alternate caption—"God, but I'll be glad to get back to Akron and the elastic-band game."—on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 102. "What floor are the Idaho women on?" (Box 7, Folder 117)
    Pencil, 12 1/4 x 18 5/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. Alternate caption—"What floor is the little Danforth child being married on?"—written in pencil on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 103. "How often do they have to share?" (Box 15, Folder 340)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 13 1/2 x 9 7/8". Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. Title—THE GIRLS By Helen E. Hokinson (her signature)- written in pencil at head of drawing.
  - 104. "Oh good! Nobody's watching." (Box 7, Folder 118)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 17", unsigned. Caption written in pencil below figures on drawing, above notation—Bridge instead—and alternate caption at foot of drawing—"Has the scoring changed much in the last twenty years?"—with notation—Tennis—in lower left corner. See Series VII, drawing 18 for a version drawn for a cover.
  - 105. "Professor Bent, may I ask you if it's true that delphiniums abhor manure?" (Box 15, Folder 341)
    Pencil, 15 x 20", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over and above previously erased and partially visible captions, and typed on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 106. "I don't know what to do, Doctor. We have one personality clash after another." (Box 7, Folder 119)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 7/8", unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased caption, with notation—(possibly just one dog in picture)—and typed with slightly altered wording on slip attached to the drawing.
  - 107. "Have you something porchy in a desk?" (Box 7, Folder 120)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing with alternate endings—tea set, love seat, secretary—in lower left corner, and typed on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 108. [Matrons talking to golf caddies.] (Box 7, Folder 121)
    Pencil, 14 x 17 1/2", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing but partially obscured by remains of a slip previously pasted over it, and with remains of a typed alternate caption on a slip attached to the drawing.
  - 109. "It reminds me of something very embarrassing that once happened to me at a wedding breakfast." (Box 7, Folder 122)
    Pencil, 12 x 18 3/4", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing above two alternate captions, with notation—In hotel lobby—in lower left corner, and notation—Miss Marion Dettinger Russell's adv. Dept.—in lower right corner.
  - 110. [Matron in fur trimmed coat, waving.] (Box 10, Folder 201)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 7/8 x 8", unsigned.
  - 111. [Two couples in evening clothes conversing.] (Box 10, Folder 202)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 3/4 x 6 3/8", unsigned.
  - 112. [Two couples in evening clothes in box at the opera.] (Box 10, Folder 203)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 x 10 7/8", unsigned.
  - 113. [Large matron and small spouse at clothing store muffler (scarf) counter.] (Box 10, Folder 204)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 5 x 10 1/4". Bottom margin cut away with remains of pencil caption visible. 1 x 2" piece missing from lower left corner with remains of Hokinson's signature visible. A1338 and N.Y. written in pencil on verso. Drawing related to #31 in Portfolio 2 and to #185 and #186 in Portfolio 3.
  - 114. The setters should be given gold medals for deportment. (Box 10, Folder 205)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 7/8 x 4·7/8"; unsigned. Title written in pencil at foot of drawing.
  - 115. "George, guess what! A very artistic woman in West Virginia is going to weave a suit for you." (Box 7, Folder 123)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 5/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased caption.
  - 116. "I gave them the dearest little cheese scoop, it must be here somewhere." (Box 7, Folder 124)
    Pencil, 12 1/4 x 18 5/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing.
  - 117. "I've just been through another tank engagement with Fletcher Pratt." (Box 7, Folder 125)
    Pencil, 14 x 18", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased caption.
  - 118. "The only way to meet the Cunningham boys is when they come ashore for ice." (Box 7, Folder 126)
    Pencil, 14 x 17", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing.
  - 119 and 120. "We're going to have to ask you to overlook a badly torn hoop skirt.", 1949 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16-7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. Accompanied by typed note from James Geraghty, dated 8/31/49, regarding sketch no. 120.
  - 121. "Ask Mrs. Porter if she could wrinkle her nose the way Gertrude Lawrence does, it will help the audience to remember who she is." (Box 7, Folder 128)
    Pencil, 14 x 16 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing over previously erased caption, partially erased notation in lower left corner.
  - 122. [Young couple in coats.] (Box 10, Folder 206)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 1/4 x 4 3/4", unsigned.
  - 123. [Two young women.] (Box 10, Folder 207)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 3/8 x 7 1/4", unsigned.
  - 124. [Scene in Italy—matron with guidebook and small dog riding in open horse-drawn carriage through ruins.] (Box 10, Folder 208)
    Black ink and watercolor, 10 x 7 5/8", unsigned. Rough sketch for cover.
  - 125. [Scene in Palestine—matron in village street.] (Box 10, Folder 209)
    Black ink and watercolor over pencil, 14 x 8", unsigned. Notation—Rough idea sketch for Palestine...—written in pencil in lower left corner. Rough sketch for cover.
  - 127. [Rear view of a woman seated in beach chair under umbrella with small dog.] (Box 10, Folder 210)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 3/8 x 6".
  - 128. [Woman and young girl with their dogs under a tree.] (Box 10, Folder 211)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 10 3/4 x 8", unsigned.
  - 129. [View of country house on a hill. (Box 7, Folder 129)
    Colored crayons over pencil, 8 7/8 x 11 7/8", unsigned.
  - 130. [Young woman posing in photographer's studio.] (Box 10, Folder 212)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 1/4, x 10 1/4", unsigned. Upper margin cut away with remains of title—(Try and get me)—visible. 3 x 4" piece cut away from lower left corner.
  - 131. [Matron standing in canoe tied up to a dock.] (Box 7, Folder 130)
    Gray wash over pencil, 9 1/8 x 12 1/4", unsigned. Tail margin cut away.
  - 132. [Four matrons entering car in front of church.] (Box 7, Folder 131)
    Watercolor over pencil, 15 x 9", unsigned. Notation—Mrs. Benedict—written in pencil at foot of drawing. Rough sketch for cover.
  - 133. "Well, there you are. We had just about given you up for lost!", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 132)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 7/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption partially erased written in pencil at foot of drawing, notation—(could be one woman in her garden)—in lower left corner. Postcard dated December 18, 1947, and sent by three Williams College students to Hokinson suggesting the idea for the drawing (garden club ladies hunting for mushrooms) is attached.
  - 134. [Matron conversing with fuel oil truck driver filling her in-ground tank.] (Box 7, Folder 133)
    Gray wash over pencil, 9 x 14 3/8", rough sketch, unsigned. Notation—Mrs. Grisner—written in pencil in upper right corner.
  - 135. [Three young women (one with ukulele) and two men in bathing costumes under umbrella painted with "New York's Great Store."] (Box 10, Folder 213)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 x 9 3/4", unsigned. Upper left and head margins cut away.
    The slogan "Greater New York's Great Store" was used by Bloomingdale's, and appeared as advertising on Westchester County beach umbrellas in the late 1920s.
  - 136. [Two matrons with three dogs at dog show.] (Box 7, Folder 134)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 10 x 9 3/8", unsigned. Erased caption partially visible at foot of drawing. Upper left and head margins cut away.
  - 137. [Two young women conversing with clerk.] (Box 10, Folder 214)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 6 7/8 x 7 7/8", unsigned. Tear in upper left margin, 1 x 1" piece missing from lower right corner.
  - 138. [Two young women conversing with man standing by pillar.] (Box 10, Folder 215)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 1/8 x 7 1/4", unsigned. 2 x 3" piece missing from upper left corner.
  - 139. [Two young women entering building between large pillars.] (Box 10, Folder 216)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 1/8 x 6", unsigned.
  - 140. [Two young women seated in subway car conversing.] (Box 10, Folder 217)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 6 x 5 7/8", unsigned. Piece from lower right margin missing.
  - 141. [Two young women in coats and hats.] (Box 10, Folder 218)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 4 3/4 x 5". Margins trimmed with loss of three letters of signature.
  - 142. This is the dog. (Box 10, Folder 219)
    Brown ink, 5 x 5 1/8", unsigned. Title written in brown ink at foot of drawing and cancelled. A2048 written in pencil on verso.
  - 143. [Two young women in coats and hats.] (Box 10, Folder 220)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 5 1/2 x 7 1/2", unsigned.
  - 144. [Rear view of two young women in coats and hats.] (Box 10, Folder 221)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 9 x 7 1/4", unsigned.
  - 145. [Fat man in cap with rose bushes.] (Box 10, Folder 222)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 6 1/2 x 5 1/4".
  - 146. [Woman in bathing suit and cape, with umbrella, walking.] (Box 10, Folder 223)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 x 8". Left and right margins cut away.
  - 147. Do You Want a Passport. (Box 10, Folder 224)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 x 7 1/4", unsigned. Title written in pencil at head of drawing and partially cut away; head margin, right margin, and 3/4 x 3" piece in lower right corner cut away.
  - 148. [Two young women in coats and hats taking an oath before an official.] (Box 10, Folder 225)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 6 3/8 x 10 1/4", unsigned. 1 x 4" piece in lower right corner cut away.
  - 149. Drawing of a house and tree. (Box 10, Folder 226)
    Watercolor over pencil, 9 x 7".
  - 150. "Where is he going, grandma?" "Hush dear." (Box 8, Folder 135)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 3/8 x 6", unsigned. 4710/18-4 written in pencil on verso.
  - 151. [Small boy looking at photos of men and women on bulletin board.] (Box 10, Folder 227)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 4 7/8 x 4 ", unsigned. 2 x 1/2" piece missing from upper right corner.
  - 152. [Elderly matron reading newspaper.] (Box 10, Folder 228)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 6 7/8 x 5 3/4", unsigned.
  - 153. The Circus Is Coming. (Box 8, Folder 136)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, unsigned. Title written in pencil at foot of drawing, and cancelled. 7837/1-/116 written in pencil on verso above a label with L7837 printed on it.
  - 154. [Rear view of two matrons in swimming suits and caps wading.] (Box 10, Folder 229)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 6 3/4 x 6", unsigned. Portion of lower left corner missing.
  - 155. [Beach scene.] (Box 10, Folder 230)
    Young woman carrying two bottles of soda-pop, and young man carrying two ice cream cones threading their way through the crowd of umbrellas and sun bathers. Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 10 3/4 x 7 3/8", unsigned. Portions of left margin missing at head and tail.
  - 156. "Oh - you must send that one to The New Yorker !" (Box 8, Folder 137)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 16 1/2 x 14 1/2". Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. 4710/18-16 written in pencil on verso.
  - 157. "Oh she always says 'Hasta luego'. It's something she picked up on the Grace Line." (Box 8, Folder 138)
    Pencil, 13 3/4 x 16 3/4", rough sketch, unsigned. Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing below, over, and above previously erased partially visible captions. Notation—a line for Goody Goodson - who, due to her extensive travel likes to use Spanish phrases, or Italian. Another character could make this remark about her.—written in pencil above and to the right of caption.
  - 158. [Chickens in cages with sign THIS SHOW DISINFECTED.] (Box 10, Folder 231)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 71/2 x 8 1/2". Title written in black ink in lower middle of drawing. 7819 written in blue crayon on verso with portions cut away.
  - 159. "I'm not even speaking to Bonnie Prince Charlie after the way he behaved in front of the judge this morning." (Box 8, Folder 139)
    Pencil, 13 7/8 x 16 3/4", rough sketch, unsigned. 3 x 2 3/4" piece cut away from upper left corner.
  - 160. Uninvited Guests. (Box 8, Folder 140)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 15 1/8 x 6 3/4", unsigned. 1463/15-13/110 written in pencil on verso.
  - 161. [Two matrons in 1920's Model T Ford.], 1931 (Box 15, Folder 342)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 12 3/4 x 19 3/4", unsigned. Tail margin cut away. A8602 written in blue crayon and date 12/5/31 in pencil on verso.
  - 162. [Two matrons seated, one in large hat with flowers.] (Box 8, Folder 141)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 13 x 8 3/4", unsigned. Left and right margins torn away. Several captions, cancelled or torn away in part, written in pencil at foot of drawing. 2047/4-2 110 written in pencil on verso.
  - 163. Youthful Aspirants for Mr. Ziegfeld's Chorus. (Box 10, Folder 232)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 11 x 8", unsigned. Title written in pencil at foot of drawing. Head margin cut away. A4058 written in pencil on verso.
  - 164. [Two matrons in short fur jackets and hats.] (Box 10, Folder 233)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 7/8 x 6 1/8", unsigned.
  - 165. "What on earth did you want to go to a place like that for?" (Box 10, Folder 234)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 10 3/4 x 8 1/2". Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing. Left, right, and tail margins cut away. A written in red crayon on verso and partly cut away.
  - 166. [Two young girls in ballet class.] (Box 10, Folder 235)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 7 1/2 x 11", unsigned. 3963/1-1-2/110 written in pencil on verso.
  - 167. The Standees have their own debate. "Now, listen, at the first of our discussion, what was it you said you didn't believe in?" (Box 8, Folder 142)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 1/2 x 15", unsigned. Title and captions written in pencil at foot of drawing, and partially cancelled. A4016 written in pencil on verso.
  - 168. Views of houses in the country side on recto and verso. (Box 8, Folder 143)
    Watercolor over pencil, 10 1/8 x 13 3/4".
  - 169. A wedding hound. (Box 8, Folder 144)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 15 x 10 1/2", unsigned. Title written in pencil. A4505 written in pencil on verso.
  - 170. Along The Seine. (Box 8, Folder 145)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 15 x 10 1/2", unsigned. Title written in pencil at foot of drawing below cancelled alternate title--Our Compatriots in Paris. A45 written in pencil on verso and partly cut away.
  - 171. "Here comes a Jade Sunrise as served by Carole Lombard." (Box 15, Folder 343)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 14 x 17 1/2". Caption written in pencil at foot of drawing above partially erased caption. AA7898 written in blue crayon on verso.
  - 172. One of the most important things to the beginner of ballet dancing is the iron rail which encircles the room. (Box 10, Folder 236)
    Just because she is learning ballet dancing is no reason why she need be old fashioned as to haircut. Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 10 3/8 x 7 1/4", unsigned. Titles written in pencil at foot of drawing. A1764 written in black ink on verso.
  - 173. [Two perplexed matrons viewing Brancusi's "Bird in Space" sculpture.], 1926 (Box 8, Folder 146)
    Black ink and gray wash over pencil, 8 7/8 x 7 1/8". A1628 written in blue ink on verso. Published on p. 28 of the February 6, 1926, issue.
  - 174. The Gramercy Park season begins. (Box 8, Folder 147)